片名：《拜见罗宾逊一家》
Meet The Robinsons
我没有选那个 因为那个会让我起疙瘩
Then I didn't choose that one because it was gonna give me pimples,
于是我挑了另外一个比较恐怖的
so I choosed another scary one
因为根据我多年参加 万圣节前夕的经验
because, for all those years that I went for Halloween,
我是比较大胆的
I wasn't scary at all.
我特爱棒球 我生下来就是要去打棒球的
I love baseball. It's my destiny to play that game.
其实我不真的那么在乎输赢
I don't really care about winning.
不过现在我挺在乎的 因为，呃，我们逢打必输
Well, like, now I do 'cause, like, we've lost every game.
我都输得麻木了
I've gotten tired of it.
我是那么卖力的打 所有的球都扔给我
I'm working, like, so hard. All the balls are getting thrown to me.
我尽力去接住每一个球
I'm trying to catch, like, every one.
场外的观众都在看着…
All of the people in the outfield are all looking around and...
走吧！ 我们打棒球去，好不?
Come on! Let's play some baseball, okay?
我们需要运动 别老呆在屋里
Not the lazy game.
他们到了
They're here.
刘易斯
Lewis?
顾博，嘿，我完成了 我做完了
Goob! Hey, I did it, Goob! I finished it!
他们将会爱死这发明
They are gonna love this!
没有比说“收养我吧” 更象古怪的发明了
Nothing says "adopt me" like a weird invention.
刘易斯
Lewis!
- 刘易斯，哈里顿夫妇到了 - 我先走了，米尔德里德
- Lewis, the Harringtons are here! - Way ahead of you, Mildred.
等等
Wait! Wait! Wait, wait, wait.
记住，坐立时要挺直腰杆 看着他们的眼睛
Remember, sit up straight. Look them in the eye.
脸带微笑 让我帮你…
Smile. Let's fix your...
米尔德里德
Mildred.
好吧，好吧
All right, all right, all right, all right.
去向他们展现你的与众不同…
Go show them how special you are.
噢，希望这次能够成功
Oh, I hope this is it.
我希望他能被收养
I hope he gets adopted.
还有我也希望，头头
You and me both, chief.
我是指这个世界上 太多东西能够改进
I mean, there's so many things in the world that can be improved.
想象一下 活动式人行道，气垫汽车
Just think of it. Moving sidewalks, flying cars.
只有想不到，没有做不到的
The possibilities are endless.
气垫汽车？嘿，我喜欢这个
Flying cars? Yeah, that's a good one.
只要少少的想象 再加上一点点的科学
All it takes is some imagination and a little science,
我们就能让这个世界变得更美好
and we can make the world a better place.
呃，这些主意非常有趣
Well, these are all interesting ideas.
那么你最喜爱的运动是什么？
So, what's your favourite sport?
- 发明创造算不算一种运动？ - 事实上…
- Well, does inventing count as a sport? - Actually...
因为当我发明了这个 我好像打了个本垒打
'Cause I think I hit a home run with this one!
- 那是啥玩艺？ - 首先，得问个问题
- What is that? - First, a question.
当你用花生酱和果子冻 做三文治的时候
What's the number one problem that you face
你面对的头号难题是什么？
when you make a peanut butter and jelly sandwich?
- 刘易斯，我不想… - 搭配比例控制
- Lewis, I don't think we... - Portion control.
太多花生酱黏住口腔顶部
Too much peanut butter sticks to the roof of your mouth,
引起咀嚼困难
takes forever to chew.
太多果子冻从三文治边上挤出来 弄得双手黏糊糊的
Too much jelly squishes out the sides and makes your hands all sticky.
我认为花生酱和果子冻的最佳搭配
Well, I propose that the perfect P.B. and J.
是人们随手可得的
is within mankind's grasp,
为此我发明了这部机器
and I've built this machine to achieve it.
在这次演示中 我使用普通的面包
For this demonstration, I'll use regular bread.
亲爱的，没事的
Honey, it's okay.
正如您所看到的 面包并不需要烤过
As you can see, toasting is an option.
我们并不吃花生酱
We don't usually eat peanut butter.
刘易斯，真的不需要演示了
Lewis, this is really not necessary.
被堵住了
It's jammed!
刘易斯，求你不要做了
Lewis, please, don't!
怎么回事？
What's happening?
哈里顿先生对花生过敏！
Mr Harrington has a peanut allergy!
真对不起！
I'm sorry!
让我帮你弄掉那些花生酱！
Here let me help you get that off!
靠后站！
Stand back!
- 他会没事吗？ - 深呼吸，深呼吸
- Is he gonna be okay? - Breathe. Breathe.
真对不起，我不知道！
I'm so sorry! I didn't know!
认识你真高兴
It was really nice to meet you.
我们需要一点时间考虑
We're gonna need some time to think about it.
嗨，一切还好吗…
Hi, folks. Everything all...
发生什么事了？
What happened?
达夫小姐 那小孩对我们绝对不合适
Miss Duffy, that boy is definitely not right for us.
现在我们告辞了
Now, if you'll excuse me.
我对发生这一切感到很抱歉 如果你们…
I'm so sorry about this. If you would just...
- 我做好午饭了 - 我不饿
- I made some lunch. - Not hungry.
可怜的哈里顿先生
Poor Mr Harrington.
- 我杀死他了？ - 没有，没有，你没有杀死他
- I killed him? - No. No! No, you didn't kill him.
我给他打电话了，他完全没事了
I called. He's perfectly fine.
我只是想说
I was just gonna say that it's...
他没有尝试一下
It's too bad he didn't get to try a sandwich
你的天才发明做的三文治 真是太可惜了
from that wonderful invention of yours.
- 对，真的太可惜了 - 这不是你的错
- Yeah, real wonderful. - It's not you.
我们只是还没有 找到合适的夫妇罢了
We just haven't found the right couple yet.
一百二十四
One hundred twenty-four.
什么？
What?
那是领养面试次数 我一共面试了124次
That's how many adoption interviews I've had, 124.
噢，刘易斯，算了吧
Oh, Lewis, come on, now.
你也太夸张了 为了说明你
You're exaggerating just to make your
是对的
point.
另外，我明年13岁了
Plus, I'm gonna be 13 next year,
你知道一个少年被领养会有多困难
and you know how hard it is for a teenager to get adopted.
我没有未来 没有人想收养我
I have no future. No one wants me.
那不是真的，刘易斯！
That's not true, Lewis!
我亲生母亲都不想要我
My own mother didn't even want me.
好了，够了，你并不知道那原因
Now, stop it. You do not know that.
那么她为什么放弃我？
Then why'd she give me up?
她或许没有能力养大你
She may not have been able to take care of you.
你有没有想过这点？
Did you ever think of that?
我肯定她所考虑的是 什么是对你最好的
I am sure that she was only thinking about what was best for you.
我从没有从那方面去想
I never thought of it that way.
或许她想养育你 但她没有能力
Maybe she wanted to keep you, but she had no choice.
你所得对
You're right.
我亲生妈妈才是唯一想要我的人
My real mom is the only person who's ever wanted me.
慢着，我是说“或许”
Wait. I said "maybe."
如果她那时要我 现在她也会要我
And if she wanted me then, she'll want me now.
你在说些什么呀？
What are you talking about?
我要去找她，米尔德里德 如果我找到她，她就会要回我
I have to find her, Mildred, and when I do, she'll take me back,
我们一家人又再重聚了
and we'll be a family again!
哦，刘易斯，你不能找到她的
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Lewis, you can't do that.
没有人知道她的任何消息 没有人曾经见过她
No one knows anything about her. No one even saw her.
不对，我看见她了
Wrong. I saw her
一次
once.
她就在我的脑海里 我只需要记起来
She's in here. I just have to remember.
就这么定了
That's it!
您好
Hello
我要告诉你一些事情
I got something to tell you
一些不可思议的事情
But it's crazy
我要给你看一些东西
I got something to show you
所以请再次给我一次机会
So give me just one more chance
再多一瞥，我对你印象更深刻
One more glance And I will make of you
有一个信仰者
Another believer
你估不到吧？ 你获得的比你索求的还多
Guess what? You got more than you bargained
太神奇了吧？
Ain't it crazy?
你买到的比你支付的还多
You got more than you paid for
所以请再次给我一次机会
So give me just one more chance
再多一瞥
One more glance
再多一只手去牵
One more hand to hold
你已经在我脑海里
You've been on my mind
虽说看似戏谑
Though it may seem I'm fooling
浪费大量时间
Wasted so much time
虽说看似戏谑
Though it may seem I'm fooling
我们将怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do about it?
你已经在我脑海里
You've been on my mind
再给一次机会
One more chance
浪费大量时间
Wasted so much time
再给一次机会
One more chance
累坏了
So tired.
我们下午两点见 你要来他会很高兴的
We'll see you at 2:00 this afternoon. He'll be so excited you're coming.
再见了
Bye-bye, now.
好极了！ 嘿，顾博…呃，是迈克尔
Yes! Hey, Goob... I mean, Michael.
- 祝你今天的大赛好运！ - 轻而易举的事情
- Good luck at the big game today. - Easy win.
对方是一群乌合之众
Those guys are a bunch of bums.
我只希望我不要睡着了
I just hope I can stay awake.
不要告诉我，让我猜猜
Don't tell me. Let me guess.
他整晚没睡 一直在搞他那该死的发明
He was up all night working on his stupid project,
但是我早就有心理准备了
but that's what happens
当你有这么一个科学怪人做室友
when you get a science geek for a roommate.
哈，真是好人
Ah, that's good joe.
好了，爱恩斯坦 你该去为迈克尔加油
All right, Einstein, you owe Michael big time.
把脑海里的秘密打开 需要的时间要比我预期的长
Well, unlocking the secrets of the brain took a lot longer than I expected,
但是已经完成了，米尔德里德 我再校准了耳机
but it's finished, Mildred. I recalibrated the headset.
现在神经中枢的线路将会接通
Now the neural circuits will connect.
我破解了脑内的海马状突起 （在泛记过程中起主要作用）
I've cracked the hippocampus!
真的吗？好的，什么？
Really? Okay. What?
现在开始测试
Now to test it out.
噢，我要迟到了，我得走了！
Oh, no! I'm late! I gotta go!
等一下，刘易斯，等一下
Wait a minute, Lewis. Wait a minute.
我差点忘了我到这的目的
I almost forgot what I came up here for.
我知道你今天有很多事情要做
I know you have a lot on your plate today,
但我已经为你安排了一次会面 在下午
but I've scheduled an interview for you this afternoon.
- 不，谢谢 - “不，谢谢”？什么意思？
- No, thanks. - "No, thanks"?
宝贝，这是关乎你被收养的大事
Sweetheart, this is about being adopted,
你得回来这里 而且要干净，高兴还有准时
and you will be back here clean, happy and on time.
我不再去会面了，米尔德里德 我不要再被拒绝了
I'm done with interviews, Mildred. I'm not gonna be rejected anymore.
听着，我知道你的想法 但我还是要提醒你
Listen, I know where your head is, but I'm telling you,
你得忘记过去 展望未来
you have got to get out of the past and look to the future.
我有，这就是了
I am, and this is it.
这就是我的未来
This is my future.
对不起
I'm sorry.
刘易斯？宝贝？
Lewis? Honey?
克伦克霍恩博士 我知道你在发明谷实验室
Dr Krunklehorn, I know you're very busy there
忙得不可开交
at Inventco Labs,
我们非常荣幸能邀请到您担任裁判
and we're just so excited to have you as a judge.
非常乐意帮忙，威勒斯坦先生 嘿，你可能还不知道
It's my pleasure, Mr Willerstein. Hey, you never know.
你的一位学生可能发明了 下一代的集成电路
One of your students may invent the next integrated circuit
或者微处理器 或者集成电路
or microprocessor or integrated circuit.
噢，慢着 我已经提过集成电路了
Oh, wait! I said that already.
我很少离开那实验室
Well, I just don't get out of that lab very much.
那是蝴蝶结吗？ 我喜欢蝴蝶结
Is that a bow tie? I like bow ties.
我有八天没有睡了
I haven't slept in eight days!
那么需要我帮你找张简易床 或其他什么的？
Well, then can I get you a cot or something?
不需要，我已经打过咖啡因补丁 这是我的发明
Nope, I've got the caffeine patch. It's my invention.
每个补丁相当于12杯咖啡
Each patch is the equivalent of 12 cups of coffee.
你能够保持清醒数天 而没有任何副作用
You can stay awake for days with no side effects.
对不起，她是谁？
Sorry. Who's this?
她是我的学生 斯坦利・普郭斯基
This is one of our students, Stanley Pukowski.
噢，太可爱了
Oh, so cute!
我真想咬一口 他那胖胖的小脸颊！
I just want to bite his chubby little cheeks!
衣服上的是什么，普郭斯基？
What's with the dress, Pukowski?
事实上这是宽外袍，先生
It's actually a toga, sir.
教练，见到你真高兴，有那么一点点 你在这干什么？
Coach, nice to see you, sort of. What are you doing here?
当科学展览的裁判啊 我看起来还会做什么？
Judging a science fair. What's it look like I'm doing?
什么让您觉得 您够资格当科学展的裁判的？
And what makes you qualified to judge a science fair?
这是我的地盘
It's my gym.
斯坦利 火山爆发吧
Stanley. Volcano.
见证维苏威火山（欧洲唯一活火山） 的神奇力量吧
Behold the awesome power of Mount Vesuvius!
触发器不工作
The toggle switch isn't toggling.
克伦克霍恩博士？
Dr Krunklehorn?
钡，钴（化学元素） 爱恩斯坦，调味剂
Barium, cobalt, Einstein, Kool-Aid!
我不知道她刚才在说什么 但这项目不通过！
I don't know what she just said, but this project is unacceptable!
现在给我环绕体育馆跑20个圈！
Now, give me 20 laps around the gym!
快跑！快跑！快跑！ 快！快！快！
Move it! Move it! Move it! Go! Go! Go!
- 教练 - 我在看着你
- Coach! - I'm watching you.
好了，下一位是莉兹和她的 火蚁（南美一种杂食性蚂蚁）养殖场
Okay, next up is Lizzy and her fire ant farm.
没错
That's right.
莉兹，我们谈论过这火蚁
Lizzy, we talked about the fire ants.
你知道他们会咬人
You know that they have a tendency to bite people.
他们只咬我的敌人
Only my enemies.
不要停，好不？ 莉兹，你是最棒的
Just keep moving, shall we? Top notch, Lizzy!
我们还是不要惹她生气 或者有任何引起她不安的举动
Let's not anger her or make her jumpy in any way.
这里不安全，进来
This area's not secure. Get in.
有没有一个戴圆顶硬礼帽 的高个子男人靠近你？
Have you been approached by a tall man in a bowler hat?
- 什么？ - 嘿，嘿，在这我来问问题
- What? - Hey, hey, I'll ask the questions here.
- 好吧，再见 - 好吧
- Okay, goodbye. - All right,
本不想以大欺小 这是你逼我的
didn't want to pull rank on you, but you forced my hand.
T.C.T.F的特别探员威尔伯・罗宾逊
Special Agent Wilbur Robinson of the T.C.T.F.
- T.C.T.F是什么来着？ - 时光统一体机动部队
- The what? - Time Continuum Task Force.
- 我是来保护你的 - 呃…
- I'm here to protect you. - Well...
现在请回答，有没有戴圆顶硬礼帽的 高个子男人靠近你？
Now, tall man, bowler hat, approached you?
没有，为什么？
No, why?
我会因为这而丢掉工作的
I could lose my badge for this.
他是一宗抢劫案的嫌疑犯
He's a suspect in a robbery.
他偷了什么了？
What did he steal?
- 一部时光机器 - 一部什么？
- A time machine. - A what?
我一直追踪他到了这个时光点 我的线人说他在找你
I've tracked him to this time, and my informants say he's after you.
找我？为什么找我？
Me? Why me?
在HQ的小伙子还没有找到他的动机
The boys back at HQ haven't figured out a motive yet.
我说的“HQ”是指总部的意思
And by "HQ," I mean "headquarters."
我知道HQ是什么意思
I know what HQ means.
很好，你是个聪明的孩子
Good. You're a smart kid.
这或许能让你活着 到目前为止
That might keep you alive, for now.
只是有点担心你那小发明
Just worry about your little science gizmo
让我来当那个“perp”（罪人）
and leave the "perp" to me.
- 我说的“perp”是指… - 我知道那是什么意思！
- And by "perp," I mean... - I know what it means!
好吧，了不起先生
Okay, Mr Smarty-pants.
戴圆顶硬礼帽的人！
Bowler Hat Guy!
我的青蛙！
My frogs!
这下你可逃不掉了
You're not gonna get away with it,
带着科学展品的小孩
kid with science project.
靓仔，你差点打烂了我的太阳能系统！
Dude, you almost busted my solar system!
我的青蛙！ 他们跑掉了！
My frogs! They're getting away!
抓到你了！ 这是最后一只
Got you! That's the last of them.
讨厌的小女孩 我可没有时间抓青蛙
Annoying little girl, I don't have time for this.
我正在执行重要的…
I'm on a very important...
对本小姐休得无礼，孩子 我会日本空手道
Don't sass me, boy. I know karate.
加油，普郭斯基！ 小小的苦楚相当于激励！
Come on, Pukowski! Feel the pain! Love the pain!
教练…
Coach...
下一个是刘易斯
Next up is Lewis.
对…刘易斯！ 失陪一下
Yes... Lewis! Excuse me.
刘易斯，告诉我这玩艺不会…
Lewis, tell me this thing is not gonna...
没事的，这次准会成功 我不会让您失望的，我保证
It's okay. It's gonna work this time. I won't let you down, I promise.
好吧，刘易斯，我相信你 给他们致命一击
All right, Lewis, I trust you. Knock 'em dead.
那是给大家一个惊喜的意思 千万不要闹出人命来
That was a figure of speech. Please don't kill anyone.
好了，大家往后站
Okay, stand back, everybody.
下一个项目会 让大家张大嘴巴合不拢
This next project will knock your socks off.
说真的，你可能需要站后一点
Seriously, you might wanna stand back a little.
你是否曾经忘记过一些事情
Have you ever forgotten something,
无论你如何努力去回想 就是想不起来
and no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't remember it?
这些被遗忘了的记忆到底去哪了？
Well, what happens to these forgotten memories?
我认为它们被存放在 我们脑海里的某个角落
I propose they're stored somewhere in your brain,
我建造了一台机器可以唤醒它们
and I built a machine that can retrieve them.
我称它记忆扫描仪
I call it the Memory Scanner.
让人眼前为之一亮！
It's shiny!
那么，刘易斯 这台记忆扫描仪的工作原理是什么？
So, Lewis, how does the Memory Scanner work?
首先，你在这键盘输入想扫描的时间段
First, you input the desired period of time on this keypad.
然后镭射扫描大脑皮层 那是记忆被存放的地方
Then a laser scans the cerebral cortex, where memories are stored.
被提取出来的记忆会 被显示在显示屏上
The retrieved memory is then displayed on this monitor.
把它打包起来 我要两台
Wrap him up. I'll take two.
现在我设定时间倒退 12年零3个月11天
Now, I'm going back 12 years, three months and 11 days.
为什么要选这个特定的日子？
Why that particular day?
我没有想到我会注意到吧？
You didn't think I was paying attention, did you?
呃，那天是…
Well, that was the day...
这么说吧 那天是我生命中很重要的一天
Let's just say, that was a very important day in my life.
比较合理 开始吧
Fair enough. Play ball.
涡轮很快就能发动起来
It'll just take a second to get the turbines going.
刘易斯，慢着！
Lewis, wait!
她要爆发了！
She's gonna blow!
注意！
Watch out!
小小苦楚相当于激励…
Feel the pain! Love the...
很疼！快停止！
Hurts so much! Make it stop!
快停止！
Make it stop!
教练，你忍住，好吧？
Coach, suck it up, okay?
让我们处理好危机 明天我们回想起也感自豪
Let us conduct ourselves in a way that we'll all be proud of tomorrow.
- 大家冷静！ - 威勒斯坦先生？
- Let's calm down! - Mr 威勒斯坦?
- 我不是故意的… - 现在不是时候，刘易斯！
- I didn't mean to... - Not now, Lewis!
对不起，真对不起
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
现在不是道歉的时候
Not now.
好吧，大家冷静有秩序地
Okay, and we are walking in a calm, orderly fashion
走向出口
toward the exits.
等等，刘易斯！
Wait, Lewis!
来，亲爱的，我们的未来在等着呢
Come, my dear. Our future awaits.
嘿，你在这干嘛？
Hey, what are you doing up here?
你能不再扮了吗，拜托了？ 我知道你不是鸽子
Would you quit that, please? I know you're not a pigeon.
你让我暴露了
You're blowing my cover.
这里只有我们两个
We're the only ones up here.
这正是他们希望你是这样想的
That's just what they want you to think.
现在，那里该打扫好了
Now, enough moping.
把这个拿回科学展 修好你的记忆扫描仪
Take this back to the science fair and fix that Memory Scanner.
停！停！离我远点！
Stop! Stop! Get away from me!
也许你忘记了
Maybe you've forgotten.
我是来自未来的时光警察 应该被非常严肃的对待
I'm a time cop from the future, should be taken very seriously.
这不是徽章
That's no badge.
这是皮肤晒成褐色沙龙赠券！ 你是个假冒的
This is a coupon for a tanning salon! You're a fake.
好吧，你揭穿了我 我不是警察
Okay, you got me. I'm not a cop,
但我确实是来自未来
but I really am from the future,
还有确实有这么一个 戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙
and there really is this Bowler Hat Guy.
又来了
Here we go again.
他偷了一部时光机器 来到了科学展
He stole a time machine, came to the science fair
破坏掉你的发明
and ruined your project.
我的发明不成功 是因为我功夫不到家
My project didn't work because I'm no good.
没有戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙 没有时光机器
There is no Bowler Hat Guy, there is no time machine,
你并不是来自未来
and you're not from the future!
你是疯了！
You're crazy!
我没有发疯
I am not crazy.
噢，对了，时光旅行队长？ 证明你所说的
Oh, yeah, Captain Time Travel? Prove it.
对了吧，我猜对了吧 你无法证明
Yeah, that's what I thought.
我要反锁自己在我的房间里
I'm just gonna go lock myself in my room
躲在掩盖物下面好几年
and hide under the covers for a couple years.
如果我证明我来自未来 你会不会回到科学展去？
If I prove to you I'm from the future, will you go back to the science fair?
好，当然，你想怎样都行
Yeah, sure, whatever you say.
嘿，放开我
Hey, let go of me!
- 你在干嘛？放开我！ - 好吧
- What are you doing? Let go of me! - Okay.
这是什么？我们要上哪去？
What is this? Where are we going?
去到未来！
To the future!
已经到达未来
The future has arrived
今天已经到达未来
The future has arrived today
已经到达未来
The future has arrived
今天已经到达未来
The future has arrived today
这个证据充足了吧？
Is this proof enough for you?
够充足了！
Is it ever!
在我一生中我从来没有 想象到时光旅行会实现
I never thought that time travel could be possible in my lifetime,
现在就在我的眼前
and here it is, right in front of me!
事实会让你相信一切 老兄
The truth will set you free, brother.
这一切超出了我的想象
This is beyond anything I could've imagined.
这意味着我完全可以改变我的生命
This means I could really change my life.
对，你能够
That's right. You can.
下一站是科学展 去修好你的记忆扫描仪
Next stop, science fair, to fix your Memory Scanner.
嘿，我才不会去修那愚蠢的记忆扫描仪
Hey, I'm not gonna fix that stupid Memory Scanner.
- 什么？ - 威尔伯，这是时光机器！
- What? - Wilbur, this is a time machine!
为什么我要去修理我那低级的发明
Why should I fix my dumb invention
什么时候你能带我去见我的妈妈？ 就用这船
when you can take me to see my mom now in this ship?
事实上我可以回到那个晚上 制止她不要遗弃我
I could actually go back to that night and stop her from giving me up.
答案不是时光机器 而是这个
The answer is not a time machine. It's this.
这个？你想知道我对这个的看法吗？
This? You want to know what I think about this?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
对不起，威尔伯
I'm sorry, Wilbur,
但你不知道我是怎样熬过来的
but you don't know what I've lived through.
- 刘易斯，不要！ - 松手！
- Lewis, no! - Let go!
- 你松手！ - 你不是我的老板！
- You let go! - You're not the boss of me!
我是的 因为我13岁，你才12岁
Yes, I am, 'cause you're 12, and I'm 13.
我比你大
That makes me older.
我在过去出生
Well, I was born in the past,
所以我比你老，你要听我的！
which makes me older and the boss of you!
我完蛋了
I am so dead.
我不允许看一眼这玩艺 更不要说驾驶它了！
I'm not allowed to look at this thing, let alone drive it!
爸爸，妈妈要杀了我了
Mom and Dad are gonna kill me,
我可以明确告诉你 他们绝不会手软的
and I can tell you this. It will not be done with mercy.
难道没有时光机器修理店
Isn't there like a time machine repair shop
- 或其他类似的？ - 没有
- or something? - No!
目前总共才有两台时光机器
There's only two time machines in existence,
另一台在戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙手上
and the Bowler Hat Guy has the other one!
那么得找人修好它
Well, somebody's gonna have to fix this.
好主意 你这么聪明，你来修
Good idea. You're smart. You fix it.
你疯了吗？我不会修这玩艺
Are you crazy? I can't fix this thing.
你行的 你弄坏了，你得修好
Yes, you can. You broke it. You fix it.
好吧，不过有个条件
All right, under one condition.
我修好了 你带我回去见我的妈妈
I fix it, you take me back to see my mom.
什么？你甚至没有兑现我们上一个协议
What? You didn't even follow through on our last deal.
这叫我如何相信你？
How can I trust you?
那么你告诉我 你是来自未来的时光警察
Well, you told me you were a time cop from the future.
这叫我如何相信你？
How can I trust you?
大家彼此彼此
Touch?
那么我们达成协议了吧？
So do we have a deal?
这位女士你好
Good day, madam.
- 我是来这改变未来的 - 是的，先生？
- I'm here to change the future. - Yes, sir?
我需要马上跟主管谈谈
I must speak with the man in charge immediately.
- 是，先生 - 我和命运有个约会
- Yes, sir. - I have an appointment with destiny.
很好，先生 我要告诉史密斯
Very good, sir. I'll let Smith know,
我会把你干洗好的衣服 直接送回到你的套间
and I'll have your dry cleaning delivered directly to your suite.
- 什么？ - 现在告诉我你的预约时间？
- What? - Now, what time is your appointment?
- 你在问我吗？ - 是的
- Are you talking to me? - Yes.
你的预约时间是几点？
What time is your appointment?
大指针在…噢，两点！
Big hand is on the... Oh, 2:00!
你是预约两点的那位？
You're the 2:00?
对，就是我
Yes. Yes, I am.
你是玛丽・约翰森？
You're Mary Johnson?
对
Yes.
玛丽是什么的简称…
Mary is short for...
玛丽安？
Marian?
- 那可以是个男孩的名字吗？ - 可以的
- Can that be a boy name? - Yes.
- 那么是的 - 请坐下
- Then yes. - Have a seat.
噢，太好了
Oh, goody!
“把发明冒认是自己的作品” 完成，噢，我喜欢清单
"Pass off invention as my own." Check. Oh, I love checklists.
管委会的人已经准备好见你
The board is ready to see you now.
等等，我该说些什么？
Wait. What am I going to say?
我永远都记不住那些
I'm never gonna remember that.
你能不能…为什么你不自己去？ 你做得比我好多了
Would you... Why don't you go? You do it so much better than me.
那是事实
That's true.
没有脑袋的帽子不可能真的
A hat without a head couldn't really pass off an invention
冒认别人的发明
as its own.
妙极了！好主意！ 真高兴有你帮忙！
Fantastic! Great idea! I'm so glad I have you!
“准备好一个惊喜” 噢，我看到了
"Prepare to be amazed." Oh, I got it!
准备好一个惊喜！
Prepare to be amazed!
“这是我的发明”
"This is my invention."
“我想在座各位从来没有 看过如此伟大的发明”
"I doubt any of you have seen anything as brilliant as this device."
非常好
Very well,
约翰森小姐？
Miss Johnson?
是太太
It's Ms.
你有两分钟时间，请开始
You have two minutes. Please begin.
- 光彩夺目！ - 那是什么？
- It's shiny! - What is that thing?
呃，我叫它为…
Well, I like to call it my...
叫它…
To call it my...
- 你在看什么？ - 没有！我…阳光照到我眼睛
- What are you looking at? - No! I... The sun, in my eyes.
那我关上百叶窗
Well, then let me close the blinds.
什么名字？
Now, the name?
呃…
Well, what...
我们可以另找个时间 讨论这名字问题
We can quibble about names at a later date.
重点是 我带来的是特别的唯一的
The point is, what I have here is special, unique.
对，对，你会爱死它 购买它和大量生产它
Yes. Yes, you must love it and buy it and mass produce it,
最妙的一点是 它带有非常舒服的耳机
and the best part is, it's got really comfy headphones.
我在想 你能够往前靠一点吗？拜托
I wonder, could you lean forward just a little bit, please?
对，谢谢
Yes, thank you.
对，它们相当舒服
Yes, they are quite comfortable.
你发明这目的是为了什么？
What do you hope to accomplish with this?
噢，没有特别的原因
Oh, nothing of consequence.
我只是想粉碎一个可怜小孤儿的梦想！
I simply wish to crush the dreams of a poor little orphan boy!
接下来就不太清楚
After that, it's all a little fuzzy.
你的意思是 你并没有全盘考虑过
You mean, you haven't thought this through?
30秒
Thirty seconds.
请允许我演示 它是如何工作的
Allow me to show you how it works.
首先，我们接通电源
First, we turn it on.
那不是开关
That's not it.
10秒
Ten seconds.
那我该在哪签名？
So where do I sign?
多里斯，一切都完了
Doris, it's all over.
我们所有的希望和梦想都破灭了
All our hopes and dreams dashed,
就像这所有的支离破碎的机器部件
like so many pieces of a broken machiney thing.
你是对的
You're right.
胜利还是属于我们的
Success is still ours for the taking.
我们必须找到那小孩
We must find that boy.
我们把这玩艺偷运到车库去 在那你需要的任何工具都有
We'll sneak this thing into the garage. You'll have all the tools you need.
那么你的父母怎办？
What about your parents?
妈妈从来不到那去
Mom never goes in there,
爸爸出差去了 明早才回来
and Dad's on a business trip until tomorrow morning.
你得赶在那之前修好它
You've got till then to fix it.
那好吧，但我需要一些 图纸或其他的一些东西
Well, fine, but I'm gonna need some blueprints or something for this.
这个不用担心 我有人会帮我们找到那些东西
No worries. I got someone who could help us with that.
何方神圣胆敢侵犯我的领地？
Who dares to disturb my sanctuary?
卡尔，是我，让我进去
Carl, it's me. Let me in.
没有人能够进去 除非他们说出正确密码
None may enter unless they speak the royal password.
卡尔，你在说啥呀？ 我们没有密码
Carl, what are you talking about? We don't have a password.
我们有个密码 你离开后我设置了一个
Yes, we do. I made one up while you were gone.
那我怎么会知道密码是什么？
Well, then how am I supposed to know what it is?
呃…
You...
你说的对
Good point.
欢迎回来，小兄弟
Welcome back, little buddy.
那台被偷的时光机器怎么啦？
So what's up with the stolen time machine?
你找到没有？显然没有
Did you find it? Apparently not,
你把这台也弄坏了
and you managed to bust this one as well.
爸爸回来前这台会被修好的
It'll be fixed before Dad gets home.
你怎么可能实现…
And how do you suppose that's gonna...
- 他是谁？ - 哇，真正的机器人！
- Who's that? - Wow, a real robot!
嗨，我是刘易斯
Hi, I'm Lewis.
真是出人意表
Well, that was unexpected.
怎么啦？
As was that.
如果我家人察觉 我把你从过去带到这
If my family finds out I brought you from the past,
他们会把我活埋了 然后在我的坟墓上跳舞
they'll bury me alive and dance on my grave.
我并没有夸张，呃，其实是有点 不过这不是问题所在
I'm not exaggerating. Well, yes, I am, but not the point.
问题是 你的头发暴露你的来历
The point is, your hair's a dead giveaway.
为什么我的头发会暴露我的来历？
Why would my hair be a dead giveaway?
问得太好了
That is an excellent question.
等一下，你要上哪去？
Wait! Where are you going?
又一个绝妙的问题
Another excellent question.
但我不想只是坐在这
But I don't just want to sit here.
留在这
Stay.
但…
But...
哇！
Wow!
嘿，按我的门铃
Hey, ring my doorbell.
不，不，不 按我的门铃
No, no, no, no, ring my doorbell.
快按，快按，快按 看着这个门铃，快按
Ring it. Ring it. Ring it. Look at this door bell. Ring it.
- 对了！ - 纯属意外
- Yes! - That was accidental.
那是不小心按的门铃 不算数
That's an accidental ring. It doesn't count.
这是手册规定的 去查查看
It's in the rule book. Look it up.
- 小平头 - 矮冬瓜
- Flat head. - Short roots.
常青藤
Evergreen.
不要让家人知道？ 你的意思是什么？
What do you mean, don't go to the family?
在这家族危机的时刻 如何能够对家人隐瞒？
How can we not go to the family in this time of family crisis?
打从不锁上车库门 时光机器因此被偷
By leaving the garage door unlocked, you let the time machine get stolen,
到现在整个时光流有可能被改变！
and now the entire time stream could be altered!
这令我忧心如焚啊
That and someone took my bike.
我告诉过你 一切都会迎刃而解
Look, I told you. It's gonna all work out.
首先，我们把刘易斯留在车库 不让其他人接触到他
First, we keep Lewis in the garage, away from everybody.
我出现给他来个世纪感言 鼓舞士气
I show up and give him the pep talk of the century.
然后他会修好时光机器
Then he fixes the time machine.
怎么会是个橡实?
Why is it an acorn?
我没时间去雕刻所有的东西
I didn't have time to sculpt everything.
好了，现在时光机器会被修好
Okay, now, the time machine is fixed.
他在发明创造的信心会恢复
His confidence in inventing is restored.
他回到科学展 修好他的记忆扫描仪
He goes back to the science fair, fixes his Memory Scanner,
因此恢复空间－时间连续流体系
thus restoring the space-time continuum.
那么带他去见他妈妈又怎么办？
What about taking him back to see his mom?
我只是跟他这么说 以便赢得时间
I just told him that to buy some time.
噢，对，从你的脸上没看到这点
Oh, yeah, can't see that one blowing up in your face.
相信我，一切都在我掌握中
Trust me. I got it under control.
威尔伯 罗宾逊从来没有失手过
Wilbur Robinson never fails.
但是有一丝极微的可能性我会…
But on the slight chance that I do...
“一丝极微的可能性”，对 你知道吧？我运算一下
"On the slight chance," yeah. You know what? I'll run the numbers.
怎么啦？
What is it?
呃，不是…
Well, it's not...
这不适于任何事情… 你知道，没这必要…
It doesn't pertain to anything in... You know, there's not necessarily...
有99.999999％可能性你将不会存在
There's a 99.999999% chance that you won't exist.
- 什么？ - 我本不想告诉你，但我说了
- What? - And I didn't want to tell you, but I did.
我不会存在？
I won't exist?
那我又会在哪？
And where does that leave me?
孤独的呆在某角落生锈
Alone, rusting in a corner.
我担心那么多干嘛？ 图纸在哪？
What am I worried about? Now, blueprints?
如果这事情结束了 我真的要摆脱你
If this thing ever blows over, I really gotta get away from you
好好的静一静
and get some quiet time.
什么…
What's...
嘿，小家伙！
Well, hey, there, little fella!
现在我知道你在想什么 就是我的衣服没有在后面
Now, I know what you're thinking, and my clothes are not on backwards.
但是我的头在后面！
My head is!
我过去常常告诉我的科学课学生
Oh, I used to tell that one to my science students.
他们也不笑
They didn't laugh, either.
无论是谁，你叫什么名字，水果头?
Anywho, what's your name, fruit-head?
- 刘易斯，但… - 刘易斯吗？
- Well, Lewis, but... - Lewis, huh?
嘿，刘易斯 你在附近没有见到过一只牙齿，是吧？
Well, say, Lewis, you haven't seen any teeth around here, have you?
- 牙齿？ - 对，我的牙齿
- Teeth? - Yeah, my teeth.
挖了一整天的洞 任何地方都没有找到
Been digging holes all day. Can't find them anywhere.
好了，老汉 我得回到车库去
All right, look, old man, I need to get back to the garage.
威尔伯把我留在那里
Wilbur left me down there,
我并不打算离开那 还有这些怪物…
and I wasn't supposed to leave, and these monsters...
- 怪物？ - …在门廊袭击我…
- Monsters? ... attacked me on the porch and...
在门廊没有怪物啊 笨蛋
There's no monsters on the porch, you ninny.
- 听我说！ - 当然，同样的我并不认为
- Listen to me! - Of course, I also didn't think
在我手臂住着只美洲旱獭
there was a woodchuck living on my arm,
嘿，你看！
and lookie there!
希望他没有携带狂犬病菌
Hope he ain't got rabies.
老头，我要回去车库！
Old man, I need to get to the garage!
一定，我马上带你到那 我有捷径
Well, sure, I'll get you there in a jiffy. I know a shortcut.
欢迎光临车库
Welcome to the garage.
我完全迷路了
Well, I'm completely lost.
您好，爷爷
Hiya, Grandpa.
嘿，比利阿姨
Hey, Aunt Billie.
刘易斯和我在找车库
Lewis and me are looking for the garage.
- 我们有个车库吗？ - 很明显是的
- We have a garage? - Apparently so.
刘易斯，能帮我一下 帮我记时吗？
Lewis, will you give me a hand and time my race?
好的，加斯顿 我的玩具火车准备好跟你比赛了
Okay, Gaston, my toy train's ready for you.
那是玩具火车？
That's a toy train?
各就各位，准备，跑
On your mark, get set, go?
- 3.7秒 - 我赢了！
- 3.7 seconds. - I win!
好吧，刘易斯 我拿到图纸了
Okay, Lewis, I got the blueprints.
刘易斯？
Lewis?
- ５，６，７，８　 　 - 这是乔叔叔，他正在健身
- And five and six and seven and eight. - That's Uncle Joe. He works out.
把腹部的脂肪除掉
Keep those tummies tucked.
这不是车库
This isn't the garage.
我知道
I know.
我也不认为车库会在里面
I don't think the garage is in here, either.
哎呀！确实是很严重的事情
Egads! A very grave matter, indeed.
- 那是阿特叔叔 - 一位真正的超级英雄？
- That's Uncle Art. - A real superhero?
四号舱，阿尔法，欧米加星系
Quad Four, Alpha Omega Galaxy,
需要一个大奶酪香肠薄面包皮的 （披萨）？
needs a large cheese-and-sausage thin-crust?
我30分钟内到 超时披萨不收钱
I'll be there in 30 minutes, or it's free.
- 他是… - 送披萨的小伙子
- He's a... - Pizza delivery guy.
刘易斯？
Lewis?
- 我们在这干嘛？ - 找车库
- What are we doing up here? - Looking for the garage.
噢，对
Oh, yeah!
拉兹洛，你不要在我的帽子上画画 否则我告诉玛！
Laszlo, you stop painting my hat, or I'm telling Ma!
- 别生气，姐姐！ - 拉兹洛，我说真的！
- Lighten up, sis! - Lasz, I mean it!
孩子们，拜托！ 你们的妈妈在小憩
Children, please! Your mother is trying to take a nap.
谁在这嚷嚷？
What is all the yelling out here?
- 他先开始的！ - 她先开始的！
- He started it! - She started it!
我不想在听到了
I don't want to hear any more!
- 现在，宝贝… - 不要叫我“宝贝”！
- Now, sweetie... - Don't you "sweetie" me!
我要开车兜风
I'm going for a drive!
那就奇怪了 她通常带上哈利
That's strange. She usually takes the Harley.
刘易斯
Lewis!
我想我太太在做曲奇饼
I think my wife Lucille's baking cookies.
露西尔，给他们做曲奇饼吧
Bake them cookies, Lucille!
为什么你的狗戴眼镜？
Why is your dog wearing glasses?
噢，因为他的医疗保险 不包括隐形眼镜
Oh, 'cause his insurance won't pay for contacts.
那是史柏克叔叔 那是季米特洛叔叔
That's Uncle Spike, and there's Uncle Dimitri.
- 噢，看，那是… - 就是那怪物
- Oh, look, there's... - That's the monster!
噢，不，刘易斯，那是我们的管家勒富q
Oh, no, Lewis, that's our butler, Lefty.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
嘿，勒富q 你知道怎样去车库吗？
Hey, Lefty, any idea how to get to the garage?
呃，对了，我们还没有去问她
Well, that's true. We didn't ask her yet.
- 谁？ - 威尔伯的妈妈，弗兰妮
- Who? - Wilbur's mom, Franny.
我想你会喜欢她的
I think you'll like her.
嘿，你们好
Hey, guys!
你一次又一次地追问我
You ask me over And over and over
你可曾看见过 我的孔雀羽毛帽子？
Have you seen My peacock-feathered hat?
青蛙？
Frogs?
教懂他们所有他们知道的
Taught them everything they know.
- 弗兰妮，这是刘易斯 - 见到你真高兴，夫人
- Franny, this is Lewis. - Nice to meet you, ma'am.
来得正好 我们需要有人打沙球(一种打击乐器)
Perfect timing. We need someone on maracas.
你的心在哪？ 没有人知道那
Where is your heart at? Nobody knows that
即使你有他，她，我
Even though you've him, her, me
还有一军队去搜索
And an army searching
我有个预感 你将被缠绕起来
I've got a feeling You will be reeling
当你不乖 马戏团刚好在城里的时候
When you are bad And the circus comes to town
爷爷，我想我找到你的牙齿了
Grandpa, I think I found your teeth.
你看着我离开 打扮得像个魔术家
And you see me leaving Dressed up as a magician
或是类似魔术家那样的
Or something like that
由撒尔沙根中提炼的药 我的牙齿回来了
Sarsaparilla! My teeth are back!
响叮当
Ring-a-ding-ding.
呼啦！
All right!
好，很高兴能帮忙找到牙齿
Right. Well, glad I could help with the teeth,
但，哇，时间不早了
but, wow, look at the time.
刘易斯，我告诉你呆在车库里
Lewis, I told you to stay in the garage!
我有，但是当我靠近那管道 我一下子跑到你的家人那里去了
I did, but I went up the tube, and I ran into your family, and I...
你见到了我的家人？
You met my family?
当场小测验
Pop quiz.
你都见过谁了 你知道些什么？
Who have you met, and what have you learnt?
好吧，伙计 弗瑞兹和乔是两兄弟
Okay. Bud, Fritz and Joe are brothers.
弗瑞兹娶了彭豚妮娜 她有点…
Fritz is married to Petunia, and is she...
古怪？是的
Cranky? Yes.
塔卢拉和拉斯洛是他们的孩子
Tallulah and Laszlo are their children.
乔娶了比利 勒富q就是管家
Joe is married to Billie. Lefty is the butler.
史柏克和季米特洛是双胞胎
Spike and Dimitri are twins,
我不知道他们之间的关系
and I don't know who they're related to.
我们也不知道 请继续
Neither do we. Go on.
露西尔嫁给了布德 你爸爸科尼利厄斯是他们的儿子
Lucille is married to Bud, and your dad, Cornelius, is their son.
科尼利厄斯的样子是怎样的？
What does Cornelius look like?
汤姆・塞勒克
Tom Selleck.
好的，科尼利厄斯娶了弗兰妮 她兄弟是加仕顿和阿特.
Okay, Cornelius is married to Franny, and her brothers are Gaston and Art.
你忘记了一点
You're forgetting something.
忘记了？噢，对
Forgetting? Oh, right.
威尔伯是弗兰妮和科尼利厄斯的儿子
Wilbur is the son of Franny and Cornelius.
没有人知道你是来自过去的？
And nobody realised you were from the past?
没有
Nope.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢你们的掌声 非常感谢
Hold your applause. Thank you very much.
多里斯，拉起来！拉起来
Doris, get it off! Get it off!
我可找到你了
I've got you now.
刘易斯
Lewis!
我不是，刘易斯是我的笨室友
No, Lewis is my stupid roommate.
我叫迈克・雅顾博伊恩 大家都叫我顾博
My name's Mike Yagoobian. People call me Goob,
但今天所有揍我的人 都叫我“恶相”
but today, everyone that beat me up called me "puke face"
还有“笨手笨脚的人” 还有“鼻涕虫”
and "butterfingers" and "booger breath."
见到他们有分歧真高兴
Nice to see that they're branching out.
对不起，我不是有意…
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
我只是来找刘易斯的
Well, I was just looking for Lewis.
去屋顶看看 他总是上去发呆
Try the roof. He's always up there being dumb.
你是对的，为什么我没有想到那？
Of course. Why didn't I think of that?
我的牛排，你是我的唯一朋友
Mr Steak, you're my only friend.
比赛不是很顺利，是吧？
Game didn't go so well, huh?
不好，我在第九轮睡着了 我没有接住制胜的一球
No, I fell asleep in the ninth inning, and I missed the winning catch.
然后我被暴揍
Then I got beat up.
接下来，教练把我叫到一边 叫我不要放在心上
Afterwards, Coach took me aside and told me to let it go.
我不知道 他可能是对的
I don't know. He's probably right.
不
No!
所有人都会告诉你别往心里去 继续往前走，但不要听他们的
Everyone will tell you to let it go and move on, but don't.
相反，让它在你内心发酵沸腾
Instead, let it fester and boil inside of you.
把这些感觉收藏起来
Take these feelings and lock them away.
让他们作为你行动的原动力
Let them fuel your actions.
让仇恨伴随着你
Let hate be your ally,
你就有能力干出 一些精彩的恐怖事情来
and you will be capable of wonderfully horrid things.
听从我的建议，顾博 不要就这么算了
Heed my words, Goob. Don't let it go.
什么？
What?
那小孩在哪？
Where is that boy?
好主意！ 分头去找线索
Good idea! Separate and look for clues.
看，亲爱的，看我找到什么了 一根木杆
Look, my dear! Look what I found! It's a stick.
你找到什么了？
Now, what did you find?
对，对，我明白
Yes. Yes, I see.
威尔伯 罗宾逊的DNA旁的 时光旅程残留物
Time travel residue next to DNA from Wilbur Robinson.
再加上我的木杆说明…
That plus my stick must mean...
到未来去！鸟枪
To the future! Shotgun!
我都不知道自己在干嘛
I don't even know what I'm doing.
保持奋勇前进
Keep moving forward.
我的意思是 这些玩艺对我来说太先进了
I mean, this stuff is way too advanced for me.
保持奋勇前进
Keep moving forward.
如果我修不好 那我们该怎办？
And what if I can't fix this? What are we gonna do?
保持奋勇前进
Keep moving forward.
为什么你老是说那句？
Why do you keep saying that?
请不要只是说 “保持奋勇前进”
And don't just say, "Keep moving forward."
那是我爸爸的座右铭
It's my dad's motto.
为什么他的座右铭会是 “保持奋勇前进”？
Why would his motto be "keep moving forward"?
他是那样做的
It's what he does.
那是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
问得好
That is an excellent question.
罗宾逊工业
Robinson Industries,
世界上领先的科研，调查和设计的工厂
the world's leading scientific-research-and-design factory.
我爸爸管理这公司 他们大批量生产他的发明
My dad runs the company. They mass produce his inventions.
他的座右铭，“保持奋勇前进” 就是他的写照
His motto, "Keep moving forward." It's what he does.
- 他都发明了什么? - 所有的一切
- What has he invented? - Everything.
卡尔，时光机器 输送管道
Carl, the time machine, the travel tubes.
你爸爸发明了时光机器？
Your dad invented the time machine?
对，5年前
Yep. Five years ago,
爸爸在半夜里醒来 一身冷汗
Dad wakes up in the middle of the night in a cold sweat.
他想建造一台时光机器 于是他开始动工
He wants to build a time machine, so he starts working.
我们谈论计划 我们谈论比例模型
We're talking plans. We're talking scale models.
我们谈论原型
We're talking prototypes.
那就是原型？
That's a prototype?
- 最原始的或者能找到的最早模型 - 哇
- The very first, or what's left of it. - Yikes.
对， 罗宾逊的黑暗日子
Yeah. Dark day at the Robinson house.
原型2号和3号 都没有好多少
Prototypes two and three, not much better.
6号，58号
Number six, 58,
212号，485号
212, 485,
952号
952,
他们都是相同的下场
and they all end the same way.
但他始终没有放弃
But he doesn't give up.
老弟，你的头那样子 我认真不起来
Dude, I can't take you seriously in that hat.
他坚持做呀做 终于他成功了
He keeps working and working until finally he gets it,
第一台成功的时光机器
the first working time machine.
他坚持做呀做 直到他再次获得成功
Then he keeps working and working until finally he gets it again,
第二台成功的时光机器
the second working time machine.
就是小了点
Kind of small.
我当作你在说笑话 由于时间的原因我不跟你计较
I'm assuming that's a joke. I'm ignoring you for time reasons.
这只是一个模型，我的朋友
This, my friend, is merely a model
因为，非常不幸， 第二台时光机器在
because, unfortunately, time machine number two
戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙手上
is in the hands of the Bowler Hat Guy.
- 相当感人的故事，对吧？ - 是的
- Pretty amazing story, huh? - Yeah.
现在你准备好开始工作了吧？
Now, are you ready to start working?
我想我完成了，我成功了！
I think that's it. I did it!
我知道你能成功
I knew you could.
干得漂亮，我的朋友
Nice work, my friend.
呃，你知道他们会怎样说 “保持向前…”
Well, you know what they say! "Keep moving..."
不要说出来
Don't say it!
孩子们，该吃饭了
Boys! Dinner time!
现在不是时候，妈妈
Not now, Mom!
如果你5分钟内还不上来 我就下去找你
If you aren't up here in five minutes, I'm gonna come down and get you!
我们最好上去
We'd better get up there.
让我们去找那小孩
Let's get that boy!
坐在这？
Sit here?
但我也想去看
But I want to look, too.
迷你多里斯！
A mini-Doris!
我甚至不知道你能够这样做 真是太可爱了
I didn't even know you could do that. It's so cute.
让我们放她出去兜兜风
Let's take her out for a spin.
对不起
Sorry.
集体合作
Teamwork.
对不起
Sorry.
Sorry!
可找到你们了
There you are.
现在把他诱出房屋
Now, to lure him out of the house.
我知道，我把房屋给炸掉 对！对…不行
I know! I'll blow it up! Yes! Yes, and... No.
那不行，他们都会死掉
No, that won't work. Then he'll be dead.
噢，我知道
Oh! I know!
我把他变成一只鸭子 对，队，真是坏透了
I'll turn him into a duck! Yes! Yes, it's so evil!
我不知道怎样变鸭子
I don't know how to do that.
我并不需要一只鸭子
I don't really need a duck.
这比我想的要难
This may be harder than I thought.
嘿，按我的门铃
Hey, ring my doorbell.
不，不，不，按这个门铃
No, no, no, no, ring this doorbell.
那个门铃会让你生疹的
That doorbell will give you a rash.
对，2比2，平手
Yes! I'm two for two, man.
如果他们不是有意识去做的 这不算数
If they don't do it on purpose, it doesn't count.
- 去，读你的手册 - 你懂什么？
- Come on. Read your rule book. - You know what?
你可以拿出你的手册 然后把它挤成正确的…
You can take your rule book and shove it right...
我不相信烦恼或悲伤
I don't believe in fretting or grieving
为什么要争斗不休？
Why mess around with strife?
我想我该放弃了 退出然后高视阔步
Guess I was cut out To step out and strut out
去过我的简单生活
Give me the simple life
先生们，女士们 上晚餐了
Ladies and gentlemen, dinner is served.
上晚餐了
Dinner is served.
呼啦！意大利菜
Hooray! Italian food.
我想吃牛肉三文治
I want a sloppy joe!
嘿，比利 你能把肉汁传过来吗？
Oh, Billie, could you please pass the gravy?
这就来，大姑娘
Coming to you, big girl.
这让我想起那次我的肉丸披萨
Reminds me of the time my meatball pizza staved off civil war
在基威诺黑色月球上击退内战
on the black moon of Keward.
我的牛肉三文治呢？
Where's my sloppy joe?
谢谢把肉汁传给我，比利阿姨
Thank you for the gravy, Aunt Billie.
- 我们得谈谈 - 要点肉汁吗？往这边
- We gotta talk. - How about some gravy? Over here.
那小孩怎么还在这？ 不知下面这些会不会让你记起什么？
Why is the kid still here? Any of this ring a bell?
科学展，记忆扫描仪， 一段需要修复的时间流？
Science fair, Memory Scanner, a time stream that needs fixing?
暂时的小障碍
Temporary setback.
他有点小小的自信心方面的问题
He's just having a little confidence issue.
- 你想要我跟他谈谈吗？ - 不需要
- You want me to talk to him? - No.
- 我给他做次适度的背部按摩？ 　- 不要
- I give a mean back rub. - No.
- 日式指压按摩？ - 不要
- Shiatsu? - No.
- 风水？ - 不要
- Feng shui. - No.
一切都在我的掌握之中
I've got it under control.
刘易斯，你和威尔伯同一个班吗？
So, Lewis, are you in Wilbur's class?
- 不是 - 是的
- No. - Yes.
- 是的 - 不是
- Yes. - No.
好吧，回答是和不是都正确
Well, yes and no.
刘易斯是刚转学到我们班的新同学
Lewis is a new transfer student.
对
Yeah.
- 你从哪来，刘易斯？ 　- 加拿大？
- Where are you from, Lewis? - Canada?
我想你是指北蒙大纳（美国州名）吧 不叫加拿大多年了
I think you mean North Montana. Hasn't been called Canada in years.
你认识萨姆・冈德森吗？
Do you know Sam Gundersen?
- 这是一个大国家啊 - 是一个州
- It's a big country. - State.
- 我想知道你们是不是亲戚 - 也许如果他把帽子脱掉了
- I wonder if you're related. - Maybe if he took his hat off.
噢，好主意
Oh, good idea.
那样我们就能看见他是不是 有家族遗传的额前翘起的一绺头发
Then we can see if he has the family cowlick.
他不能 因为他的头发很难看，得用帽子盖住
He can't, because he's got bad hat-hair.
噢，胡说
Oh, nonsense.
北蒙大纳人才不会在乎 自己的“帽子头发”
A North Montana man doesn't care about hat-hair.
让我们看看你的额前翘起的那绺头发
Let's see the cowlick!
好了，各位，约束一下自己
All right, everyone, hold your horses.
刘易斯，你介意吗？
Lewis, do you mind?
我恐怕（你不给他们看） 他们不会就此罢休的
I'm afraid this isn't gonna stop otherwise.
- 但…但… - 那么开战吧
- But... But... - And so it begins.
别害羞
Now, don't be shy.
- 这里我们都是一家人 - 准备，瞄准，开火！
- We're all family here. - Ready, aim, fire!
当然，你一定能够做的更好
Surely, that is not the best you can do.
令人刮目相看啊，小妹
Impressive, little sister.
你的能力很强 但还没强到足以跟我抗衡
Your skills are strong, but not strong enough.
你的话吓唬不了我的，大哥
Your words do not threaten me, brother.
那就废话少说 现在正式开战吧
Then enough words. Now the real battle begins.
你的肉丸对我毫无作用
Your meatballs are useless against me.
那么也许该到 意大利辣香肠上场了
Then perhaps it's time for spicy Italian sausage!
不！
No!
这就对了 我做到了
That's right. I did it.
每天的晚饭都这样吗？
Is dinner like this every night?
不是，昨天我们吃肉卷
No, yesterday, we had meatloaf.
好了，大伙儿 现在上第二道菜
Okay, gang, time for the second course.
还有什么比花生酱与果子冻 和肉丸搭配更好的呢？
And what goes better with meatballs than P.B. and J?
嘿，那个好像…
Hey, that's just like...
愚蠢的…
Stupid...
卡尔？
Carl?
一切还好吗？
Is everything all right?
我们碰到一些缺陷
We're just experiencing bugs.
真是千载难逢
Just what the doctor ordered.
我朋友刘易斯是个发明家 他能修好
My friend Lewis is an inventor. He can fix it.
威尔伯，你知道我不行
Wilbur, you know I can't.
来吧，试试看
Come on. Give it a try.
你不知道，事关重大
You don't understand what's at stake here.
乔叔叔已经看见了面包
Uncle Joe's seen the toast!
我们已经到了危急关头 不能后退了
We're past the point of no return!
如果他得不到花生酱和果子冻
If he doesn't get P.B. and J...
我们代价惨重！
We all pay!
我不知道
I don't know.
你一定要帮我们渡过这次危机 刘易斯
You would really be helping us out, Lewis.
拜托了
Please.
酒吧老板，请来杯“岩上蜻蜓”
One dragonfly on the rocks, please, Mr Barkeep.
嘿，嘿， 弗兰克，宝贝 你得跟我们说个笑话
Hey, hey, Frankie, baby, you gotta tell us one of your jokes.
对， 弗兰克 那个关于牛蛙的笑话怎样？
Yeah, Frankie. How about that one with the bullfrog?
好吧，你们这些家伙
All right, you bozos.
得把那小孩引出那房屋
Have to get that boy out of the house.
对不起，等等！
Sorry. Wait!
于是我转向牛蛙 你们猜我说了什么？
So I turn to the bullfrog, and you know what I says?
会说话的青蛙 在他们自己的小室外酒吧
Talking frogs with their own little outdoor bar,
还穿得这么得体 太棒了！
and so smartly dressed! Perfect!
我说 “嘿，我没有带伞，你不要…”
I says, "Hey, not with my umbrella, you don't."
-  弗兰克，你可真逗 - 我要去拉尿
- Frankie, you're a riot. - I gotta go pee!
- 我喜欢这笑话 - 一群傻瓜
- I love it. - You bunch of goons.
这嗡嗡声真好听 他妈…
That's a good buzz. What the...
对了，你现在受我控制了
Yes! You are now under my control.
我现在受你控制了
I am now under your control.
- 不要笑 - 不要笑
- Stop laughing. - Stop laughing.
- 不要重复我说的每一句话 - 我不重复你说的每一句话
- Don't repeat everything I say. - I won't repeat everything you say.
- 好极了 - 好极了
- Excellent. - Excellent.
你也说“好极了” 是不是因为我说了“好极了”？
Did you just say, "Excellent," because I said, "Excellent"?
不是
No.
- 好极了 - 好极了
- Excellent. - Excellent.
- 请问修理先生，事情进展如何？ - 很好， 罗宾逊夫人
- So, Mr Fix-it, how's it looking? - Pretty good, Mrs Robinson.
我已经重新校准了输送管道
I've recalibrated the dispensing conduits
并且调直了发射装置…
and aligned the ejection mechanism and...
那就是他 那个讨厌的，愚笨至极的傻瓜！
There he is, that repulsive, half-witted fool!
现在去抓住那小子，我的奴隶
Now, my slave, seize the boy.
把他带来给我
Bring him to me.
你没听见我的话吗，笨蛋？ 去抓那小子带来给我
Did you not hear what I said, you idiot? Grab the boy and bring him!
呃，问题是 那边有那多人
Well, it's just that there's a million people over there,
而我只有两双小手
and I have little arms.
我不太确定 这计划有没有经过深思熟虑
I'm just not so sure how well this plan was thought through.
主人？
Master?
好了，这应该可以了
Okay, that should do it.
太激动了，让她射吧，刘易斯
It's so exciting. Let her rip, Lewis!
赶快，乔叔叔快支撑不住了
Quickly. Uncle Joe can't hold on much longer.
大家都准备好了？
Everybody ready?
- 开始吧，卡尔 - 对
- Go, Carl. - Yeah!
它现在工作了吗？
Is it gonna work?
哦，不！
Oh, no!
不！
No!
我不知道 对不起，真的对不起
I didn't know. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- 你失败了！ - 了不起！
- You failed! - And it was awesome!
- 真不可思议！ - 太优秀了！
- Exceptional! - Outstanding!
我见过更好的
I've seen better.
从失败中可以学到很多 从成功中，只能锦上添花
From failing, you learn. From success, not so much.
如果我每次失败就选择放弃
If I gave up every time I failed,
我永远也造不出我的肉丸大炮
I never would have made the meatball cannon.
我永远发明我不了我的防火裤
I never would have made my fireproof pants.
很明显还有很多问题需要解决
Still working out the kinks.
正如我丈夫常说的…
Like my husband always says...
勇往直前… 勇往直前…
Keep moving Keep moving
停
Stop
好吧，会说话的青蛙不是个好奴才
Okay, talking frog, not a good minion.
需要另外找个同党 块头大，不要太聪明
Need another henchman, something large, not too bright.
不会跟我顶嘴的家伙
Something that won't talk back.
他还在这干嘛？ 把他干掉
What is he still doing here? Get rid of him.
噢，我的头
Oh, my noggin.
嘿，你干什么？ 把你的脏手拿开
Hey, what are you doing? Get your lousy mitts off of me!
你将会为你所做的一切后悔的
You're gonna regret this!
等等！等等！别动，就是它了
Wait! Wait! Don't move. That's it!
我是不是该告诉多里斯呢
I wonder if I should tell Doris.
不，给它一个惊喜吧
No, I'll make it a surprise.
好了，大家静一静 静一静
All right, everyone, quiet down. Quiet down.
我提议为刘易斯和他的锦绣前程干杯
I propose a toast to Lewis and his brilliant failure.
祝他在未来取得巨大的成功
May it lead to success in the future.
天哪，你们太好了
Gosh, you're all so nice.
如果我有个家庭，我…
If I had a family, I...
我希望他们就跟你们一样
I'd want them to be just like you.
哦，那好，为刘易斯干杯！
Oh, well, then, to Lewis!
为刘易斯干杯！
To Lewis!
太好了
Yeah!
- 来吧，刘易斯！ - 表现出色，伙计
- Come on, Lewis! - Good show, buddy!
假如路易斯・阿姆斯壮说“我不能”
What if Louis Armstrong said, "I can't"?
你认为他还能登上月球吗？
You think he'd have walked on the moon?
亲爱的，路易斯・阿姆斯壮是位歌手
Dear, Louis Armstrong was a singer.
他说“如果他有个家庭的话” 是什么意思？
What did he mean, if he had a family?
哦，刘易斯是个孤儿
Oh, Lewis is an orphan.
孤儿？
Orphan?
- 哦， 不！ - 巨无霸！
- Oh, no! - Big boy!
起来，你这个脂粉气男人
Get up, you pansy!
多么绝妙的计划啊！
What a great plan!
回到过去偷一个恐龙回来 噢，多里斯会为我感到多么的自豪
Go back in time and steal a dinosaur. Oh, Doris will be so proud of me.
你怎么没告诉我 你养了一条恐龙宠物？
Why didn't you tell me you had a pet dinosaur?
因为我们根本没养
Because we don't.
你在说什么呢？ 它就站在那里
What are you talking about? He's standing right here.
哦，不！不，你不能吃掉他
Oh, no! No, you can't eat him!
我要活的
I need him alive.
火车去对付它！
Choo-chew on this!
刘易斯！
Lewis!
准备，瞄准，开火！
Ready, aim, fire!
接住你了
Got you!
你惹错家族了
You messed with the wrong family!
叮咚！披萨到了
Ding-dong! Pizza's here!
不！
No!
好了，大伙，这恐龙成了披萨馅了
Okay, everybody, this dino's deep-dished.
快跑
Run!
哦，他把卡尔吃掉了！
Oh! He ate Carl!
- 帮帮我们！救命啊！ - 噢，天哪！
- Help us! Help! Help! - Oh, goodness!
噢，不！
Oh, no.
打进去
Incoming!
快跑
Run!
现在去抓那小子！
Now, go get that boy!
怎么回事？
What's going on?
怎么不去抓住他？
Why aren't you seizing the boy?
我的头太大…
I have a big head...
手太小
...and little arms.
我不太确定
I'm just not sure...
这计划有没有经过深思熟虑
...how well this plan was thought through.
主人？
Master?
蠢材，蠢材，蠢材！
Stupid, stupid, stupid!
戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙
Bowler Hat Guy!
你能够吃掉他
Him you can eat.
- 刘易斯，快跑！ - 威尔伯！
- Lewis, run! - Wilbur!
不！
No!
噢，不！
Oh, no!
小多里斯现在要与鱼同眠了
Little Doris now sleeps with the fishes.
- 接得好 - 肉丸射击漂亮！
- Nice catch. - Nice meatball shooting!
看来我们是最佳拍档，对吧？
Guess we made a pretty good team, huh?
是啊，我们确实是的
Yeah, guess we did.
- 孩子们，你们没事吧 ？ - 我们很好，妈妈
- Are you boys all right? - We're good, Mom.
你没看到我们怎么打败那恐龙吗？
Yeah, didn't you see us take out that dinosaur?
哦，酷毙了，妈妈！
Oh, man! It was so cool, Mom!
噢，我意思是，对不起，我没…
Oh, I mean, I'm sorry. I didn't...
噢，刘易斯，不要紧
Oh, Lewis, it's okay.
你没事我真的感到很高兴
I'm really happy you're safe.
- 你的头 - 什么？
- Your head. - What?
哦，只是擦伤，刘易斯
It's just a bruise, Lewis.
你们都为我付出了那么多
You all sacrificed so much for me.
- 那是应该的 - 你是个很特别的孩子
- Well, of course. - You are a special kid.
独一无二的
One of a kind.
好了，在一些真正很糟糕的事情 发生之前，你该把他带走
Okay, you should get him out of here before something really bad happens.
傻乎乎的笨机器人 一切都在我的掌握中
Silly, silly robot. I've got it all under control.
好的，大伙们 今天大家都辛苦了
Okay, everybody, it's been a long, hard day
整天都是感情风波 还有恐龙大战
filled with emotional turmoil and dinosaur fights,
所以大伙都回去睡觉吧 我和刘易斯要走了
so why don't you all hit the hay, and Lewis and me will get going?
你必须得现在走吗？ 我的意思是，现在已经很晚了
Do you have to go now? I mean, you know, it's getting late.
也许刘易斯能在这住一晚
Maybe Lewis could spend the night.
妈妈，以后再找个时间吧，好吗？
Mom, maybe some other time, okay?
好吧，任何时候你想过来 我们都欢迎
Well, any time you want to come over, you just come over.
- 妈妈 - 事实是我们喜欢有你在
- Mom. - The truth is, we love having you.
- 我们真的得走了 - 不
- We really have to go. - No.
不，你不需要走，你得留下
No, you don't. You have to stay.
我的意思是，还有哪个家庭 比我们的家庭更适合你呢？
I mean, who would be a better family for you than us?
你觉得呢，刘易斯？
What do you say, Lewis?
你想成为罗宾逊家庭的一成员吗？
Do you want to be a Robinson?
你想收养我吗？
You want to adopt me?
是的！ 太好了！
- Yeah! - Yes!
好吧，事实上我是来自过去
Okay, it's true. I'm from the past.
现在你们都知道这个大秘密了
Now you know the big secret.
威尔伯，你都干了些什么？ 你怎么能把他带到这里来？
Wilbur, what have you done? How could you bring him here?
这个问题问得好
That is an excellent question.
请不要对威尔伯生气
Please, don't get mad at Wilbur.
他只是想帮我
He was just being a good friend.
刘易斯，很对不起 但你必须得走
Lewis, I am so sorry, but you have to go.
什么？你刚才还说…
What? You just said...
我知道我刚才说了什么
I know what I said.
我来自过去，又怎么样？
I'm from the past. So what?
刘易斯，看着我，你是个…
Lewis. Lewis, look at me. You're...
你是个好孩子
You're a great kid,
我们决不愿意做任何事情去伤害你
and we would never do anything to hurt you,
但对不起 你必须得回到属于你的时间
but I'm sorry. You have to go back to your own time.
对了，关于这点 其中一台时间机器坏了
Yeah, about that, one of the time machines is broken,
另外一台被戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙给偷了
and the other one was stolen by a guy with a bowler hat,
这可以解释这恐龙为什么会出现
which kind of explains the dino.
我去打电话给你爸爸
I'm calling your father.
慢着，如果我不得不离开
Wait. If I have to leave,
至少我能回到过去找我的妈妈吧？
can I at least go back and find my mom?
威尔伯答应过我的
Wilbur promised.
你答应他什么啦？
You promised what?
我永远都不会兑现的 我发誓
I was never gonna do it. I swear!
- 你对我撒谎？ - 没有
- You lied to me? - No!
是的
Yes.
刘易斯！刘易斯，等等
Lewis! Lewis, wait!
我不敢相信我真是傻得可以 居然真的相信你是我的朋友
I can't believe I was dumb enough to actually believe you were my friend!
我是你朋友！
I am your friend!
先生，你永远都不允许外出 永不翻案
Mister, you're grounded till you die.
噢，是啊，多里斯，真是可惜了
Oh, yes, Doris, it is a shame.
他一心想做的只是回到过去 和自己从没见过的母亲会面
All he wants to do is go back in time to meet the mother he never knew,
但他们却不让他去 不过我们却乐意
but they won't let him. We'd let him, though.
只可惜我们没有时光机器
Too bad we don't have a time machine.
噢，慢着，我们有一台
Oh, wait. We do.
戴圆顶硬礼帽的家伙？
Bowler Hat Guy?
- 你好，刘易斯 - 你想干什么？
- Hello, Lewis. - What do you want?
来让你梦想成真
To make your dream come true.
你所要做的就是把 这笨重的玩艺重新装好
All you have to do is put Humpty Dumpty back together again,
我们就带你回去找你妈妈
and we'll take you back to find your mommy.
刘易斯！
Lewis!
让我们好好谈谈吧，刘易斯 出来吧！
Let's just talk about this, Lewis. Come on!
我知道你就在附近某处
I know you're around here somewhere.
刘易斯！
Lewis!
我想不通你为什么会对 这件垃圾感兴趣
I can't imagine why you're so interested in this piece of junk.
那是我自己知道的事 你自己去了解发现
That's for me to know and you to find out.
现在告诉我怎么操作这玩艺
Now, show me how to work this thing.
它运转不了，从来就没有工作过
It doesn't work. Never did.
那么假设它能运转
Well, supposing it did,
如果有人把这个发明展示给，例如
and if one were presenting the invention to, say,
一家很大的发明公司的董事会
a board of directors for a very large invention company,
他在哪可以找到那“启动”的开关？
where might one find the "On" switch?
当然，这只是一个假设
Hypothetically speaking, of course.
好吧，首先，你旋转这个旋钮两次
All right, first, you turn this knob twice,
然后按这个红色的按钮
then push this red button,
这就行了，很简单吧
and that's it. It's pretty easy.
这方式启动机器真是蠢得可以！
What a stupid way to turn it on!
好吧，现在带我去见我的妈妈吧
Okay, take me to see my mom now.
好的，当然了
Yes, of course.
多里斯？
Doris?
我们谈好条件的！
We had a deal!
我的手指交叉的 所以不算数
Crossies! Doesn't count.
你为什么这样对我？ 我没有做过任何对不起你的事啊
Why are you doing this to me? I never did anything to you.
你还没有弄明白吗？
You still haven't figured it out?
弄明白什么？
Figured out what?
那么看看这能不能让你记起什么
Well, let's see if this rings a bell.
未来之父 卓越的发明家
Father of the Future, inventor extraordinaire,
“勇往直前”？
"Keep moving forward"?
那不是我 那是威尔伯的爸爸
That's not me. That's Wilbur's dad.
你是在说
Are you saying
我就是威尔伯的爸爸？
that I'm Wilbur's dad?
答对了 该给你一份奖品
Give the boy a prize.
你长大成为这悲惨时代的奠基人
You grew up to be the founder of this wretched time,
所以我计划去破坏你的定数
so I plan to destroy your destiny.
- 很容易的 - 那么…
- Easy peasy, rice and cheesy. - Well...
如果我是威尔伯的爸爸…
So if I'm Wilbur's dad...
继续想下去
Keep going.
如果我是威尔伯的爸爸…
If I'm Wilbur's dad...
是的，谢谢 ，我们已经知道这点了
Yes, thank you, we've established that.
但那跟你有什么关系？
But what does that have to do with you?
请允许我开灯照亮这个物体
Allow me to shed some light on the subject.
我的老睡房！
My old room!
你想你是指我们的老睡房吧
I think you mean our old room.
- 什么？ - 是的！是我
- What? - Yes! Yes, it is I,
迈克・雅顾博伊恩！
Mike Yagoobian!
我知道，我很恶心，但你要学着去喜欢
I know. I'm disgusting, but one learns to love it.
你怎么会变成这样的？
How did you end up like this?
说来话长且令人同情 那是关于一个满怀希望男孩的故事
Well, it's a long and pitiful story about a young boy with a dream,
梦想赢得一个小小的联赛冠军
a dream of winning a Little League championship,
但这个梦想在最后一轮破灭了
a dream that was ruined in the last inning.
因为我的过错 我们输掉了比赛，就因为最后一轮
We lost by one run because of me.
揍扁他！
Get him!
如果我没有睡着 我就能接住那球
If I hadn't fallen asleep, I would have caught the ball!
我们就会赢
And we would have won!
你们明白吗？
Do you understand?
因为某些原因 没有人愿意领养我
For some reason, no one wanted to adopt me.
神童科尼利厄斯・罗宾逊14岁便大学毕业
Whiz kid Cornelius Robinson graduates from college at age 14.
本年度诺贝尔奖的获得者 是年轻的科尼利厄斯・罗宾逊
This year's Nobel Prize goes to a young Cornelius Robinson.
嘿，顾博，你好吗？好漂亮的文件夹
Hey, Goob, what's up? Cool binder.
嘿，顾博，今天到我家玩吗？
Hey, Goob, wanna come over to my house today?
他们都恨我
They all hated me.
后来，他们关闭了孤儿院 所有人都走了
Eventually, they closed down the orphanage and everyone left,
除了我
except me.
科尼利厄斯・罗宾逊重建了发明谷公司
Cornelius Robinson rebuilds Inventco.
- 罗宾逊涉足… - 新名字…
- Robinson reaches out to... - It's new name,
- 罗宾逊工业公司 - 科尼利厄斯・罗宾逊
- Robinson Industries. - Cornelius Robinson!
- 科尼利厄斯・罗宾逊现在… - 又一件令人惊奇的…
- Cornelius Robinson is now... - Now here's another amazing...
就在那时候 我知道那不是我的错
It was then that I realised it wasn't my fault.
而是你的错
It was yours.
如果你没有让我熬一整夜 帮你做那蠢发明
If you hadn't kept me up all night working on your stupid project,
那么我就不会接不住那球
then I wouldn't have missed the catch,
于是我想出了一个辉煌的复仇大计
so I devised a brilliant plan to get my revenge.
罗宾逊，你坏透了！
Robinson, you stink!
就在我准备要破坏 罗宾逊工业公司的时候
Then, just as I was on the brink of destroying Robinson Industries,
我遇见了她
I met her.
我们撤回到我们那邪恶的巢穴
We retreated to our villainous lair,
在那里多里斯全告诉了我 她被欺骗和无比痛苦的故事
where Doris spun a tale of deception and woe.
很明显，你发明她的初衷是 想让她成为“帮助帽”
Apparently, you invented her to be a Helping Hat,
听命于人类
a slave to humankind,
但多里斯知道她的能力 远远超出这范围
but Doris knew she was capable of so much more.
但是你没有看到她的真正潜力
However, you didn't see her true potential.
- 受够了 - 于是你关闭了她
- Got it. - So you shut her down,
大概你以为你关闭了她
or so you thought.
我们俩都想找你算账
We both had a score to settle with you,
虽然我的复仇计划如此精妙，多里斯…
and while my plan for revenge was brilliant, Doris' was...
好吧，我们还是选多里斯的计划
Well, we went with Doris',
但是我做出了非常非常重要的贡献
but I made a very, very important contribution.
我们俩一起是最佳拍档
Together we made the perfect team.
威尔伯！
Wilbur!
确定你把那门关严实了 否则警报就不起作用了
Make sure you shut that door tight, or else the alarm won't engage.
好的，妈妈
Yeah, Mom.
我去到你家，偷偷地溜进车库
I went to your house, snuck in the garage
偷走了时光机器
and stole the time machine,
这全靠那个额头前有尖尖头发的小孩 忘记了关那车库门
all thanks to that pointy-haired little kid who forgot to lock the garage door.
现在所需要做的就是回到发明谷
And now all that's left is to return to Inventco,
在那里我把你的小发明冒认是我的
where I'll pass off your little gizmo as my own.
但你不知道 那会给这未来造成什么样的影响！
But you have no idea what that could do to this future!
那我可不管 我只想毁掉你的生活
I don't care. I just want to ruin your life.
顾博，我不明白
Goob, I had no idea.
闭嘴，不要叫我顾博
Shut up! And don't call me Goob!
你知道有多少坏人 可以叫顾博这样的名字？
How many evil villains do you know who can pull off a name like Goob?
我很抱歉你的生活变得这么差
Look, I'm sorry your life turned out so bad,
但不要责怪我 是你自己弄得一团糟的
but don't blame me. You messed it up yourself.
你只是把注意力集中在坏的事情上面 你所需要做的就是…
You just focused on the bad stuff when all you had to do was
让过去的一切随风消失 勇往直前
let go of the past and keep moving forward.
让我们比较一下
Let's see.
对我自己生活负责还是责怪你
Take responsibility for my own life or blame you.
“责怪你”轻易胜出
"Blame you" wins hands down!
这将是我生命中最精彩的一天
This is gonna be the best day of my life!
多里斯，您能做做好事 帮我打开舱门吗？拜托
Doris, would you be a dear and open the hatch for me, please?
不！
No!
我不想破坏你邪恶的计划 然后跑掉，但是再见！
Well, I hate to foil your evil plan and run, but ta-ta!
但…
But...
我想你一定很高兴见到我
I bet you're glad to see me.
这是惩罚你没有关好车库门
That's for not locking the garage door.
你都知道那？
You know about that?
我什么都知道
I know everything.
你得承认
You gotta admit,
这会是一个很好的故事 哪一天你可以跟我讲起
this will be a great story to tell me someday.
你们快看，孩子们 我们就要成功到家了
Look at that, boys. We're almost home free.
噢，不！
Oh, no!
好好看一下吧，孩子们
Take a good look around, boys,
因为你们的未来就要改变了
because your future is about to change.
刘易斯，你得把时光机器修好
Lewis, you have to fix the time machine.
不，不，我不能
No. No, I can't.
你爸爸怎样？ 你可以去找他
What about your dad? You could call him.
- 你就是我爸爸 - 但那是在未来的事情
- You are my dad. - But that's in the future.
未来将要不存在了 除非你修好时光机器
There won't be a future unless you fix the time machine.
是我把事情弄得乱七八糟的
Look, I messed up.
我没有关好车库门 我拼命地努力试图弥补一切
I left the garage unlocked, and I've tried like crazy to fix things,
但现在都看你的了
but now it's up to you.
你能做到的，爸爸
You can do it, Dad.
- 刘易斯？刘易斯！ - 威尔伯？威尔伯！
- Lewis? Lewis! - Wilbur? Wilbur!
威尔伯
Wilbur.
罗宾逊夫人？阿特叔叔？勒富q？
Mrs Robinson? Uncle Art? Lefty?
准备好大开眼界吧
Prepare to be amazed.
我叫它记忆扫描仪
I call it the Memory Scanner.
那么，雅顾博伊恩 还有什么其他想法要和大家分享吗？
So, Yagoobian, any other ideas you'd like to share with us?
是的，我叫它们帽子助手
Yes. I call them Helping Hats.
它们无处不在
They're everywhere!
多里斯，发生什么事情？ 我搞不懂
Doris, what's happening? I don't understand.
我只是想毁掉他的未来 我并不想事情变成这样啊
I just wanted to ruin his future, not this.
不！
No!
不 不，这一切不可能会发生的！不！
No. No, this can't be happening! No!
噢，刘易斯，这已经发生了
Oh, Lewis, it's already happened.
我为什么会发明那荒谬的帽子？
Why did I ever invent that stupid hat?
看仔细了，多里斯 因为你的未来就要改变了
Take a good look around, Doris, 'cause your future's about to change.
顾博，停下！
Goob, stop!
你不知道自己在干什么
You don't know what you're doing!
我知道 我在毁掉你的未来
Yes, I do. I'm ruining your future.
她在利用你，顾博
She's using you, Goob,
当她得到了她想要的东西 她就会把你干掉
and when she gets what she wants, she'll get rid of you.
什么？什么？
What? What?
我将永远都不会发明你
I am never going to invent you.
来吧，顾博 我带你去看一些东西
Come on, Goob. I've got to show you something.
多里斯？
Doris?
我以为她是我的朋友
I thought she was my friend.
你做到了，刘易斯 你成功了！
You did it, Lewis. You did it!
我拖住他 你快去搬救兵
I'll hold him while you run for help.
放开他
Let him go.
你是怎么啦？ 他是个坏蛋
What are you doing? He's the bad guy.
不，他不是 他是我的室友
No, he's not. He's my roommate.
- 什么？ - 他是我的老室友
- What? - He's my old roommate,
我真的觉得你们应该收养他
and I really think you guys should adopt him.
- 你疯了吗？ - 为什么不？给我一个好的理由
- Are you nuts? - Give me one good reason why not.
我给你三个好理由
I'll give you three good reasons.
他偷了我们的时光机器 企图毁掉你的未来
He stole our time machine, tried to ruin your future,
还有他闻起来好像有30年没洗澡了
and he smells like he hasn't showered in 30 years!
请允许我提醒你一下 我是你爸爸，你得听我的
May I remind you, I'm your father, and you have to do what I say.
好吧，雅顾博伊恩先生，你想成为…
Okay, Mr Yagoobian, do you want to be a...
- 他去哪了？ - 顾博？
- Where'd he go? - Goob?
顾博！
Goob!
顾博
Goob.
你受伤了吗？ 有没有骨折？
Are you hurt? Any broken bones?
- 没有，我… - 你量了体温没有？
- No, I'm... - Do you have a temperature?
- 脑衰竭？ - 坏血病？
- Brain fag? - Scurvy?
- 绦虫病？ - 脂肪团？
- Tapeworm? - Cellulite?
不，不，我很好，我感觉很好
No. No, no, I'm fine. I feel fine.
实际上 很久没感觉这么好了
In fact, better than I've felt in a long time.
弗兰妮，它们不见了 噢，这糟透了
Franny, they're gone. Oh, this is terrible!
- 噢，天哪 - 他提早到家了
- Oh, boy. - Well, he's home early.
弗兰妮，你在哪？ 时光机器都不见了
Franny, where are you? The time machines are gone!
被老女人出卖了
Ratted out by the old lady.
残酷啊
Harsh.
好了
Okay.
是啊，每天都在办公室里不懈的工作
Yeah, beats working in an office every day.
对，那是一定的了
Yeah, no kidding.
嘿，想看看我最引以为豪的那个吗？
Hey! Want to see the one I'm most proud of?
好啊
Yeah.
不，不，不，不 是那个
Oh, no, no, no. That one.
这是我们的第一个真正的发明
It was our first real invention.
这所有的一切都是由那开始的
It's the one that started it all.
哇靠
Wowie.
那么如果我现在回去 这将是我的未来
So if I go back now, then this will be my future.
那就取决于你了
Well, that depends on you.
没有什么事情是一成不变的
Nothing is set in stone.
你需要做出正确的决定 然后保持奋勇前进
You gotta make the right choices and keep moving forward.
既然这次看上去一切都好 是不是意味着我…
Since it's gonna work this time, that means I...
我们最后将不会去看 妈妈是什么样子的？
We won't finally get to see what Mom looks like?
我们有没有见到她？
Do we ever meet her?
我想你得回到科学展
I think you're just gonna have to get back
自己去找答案
to that science fair and find out for yourself.
我就知道你会这么说
I had a feeling you were gonna say that.
那是因为我们俩是一个聪明的小孩
That's because we are one smart kid.
- 再见 - 再见，刘易斯！
- So long! - Bye-bye, Lewis!
- 再见，未来的姐夫 - 保重！再见，刘易斯！
- Farewell, future brother-in-law. - So long! See you later, Lewis!
噢，别忘了马铃薯泥
Oh, don't forget the mashed potatoes!
- 一路平安，小刘易斯 - 我会的
- Have a safe trip, little Lewis. - I will.
嘿，既然你在这
Hey, while I got you here,
有一些关于我设计方面的 小小的建议
just a couple of little suggestions regarding my design.
实话实说吧，这手臂太细了 拎起茶壶都困难
Let's face it, these skinny limbs don't exactly make the teapot whistle.
其实最重要的一点 嘿，千万别忘了发明我
All that really matters is, hey, don't forget to invent me.
- 你在开玩笑吧？那怎么可能忘了！ - 我爱你
- Are you kidding? No way! - I love you.
有太多的事情 我希望能够问你
There's so many things I wish I could ask you.
对不起，现在要时光旅行了 问题留待以后再问吧
Excuse me. Time travel now, questions later.
- 但我… - 别担心
- But I... - Don't worry.
你只要回到那科学展 我们很快又再见面了
Just get back to that science fair, and we'll see you real soon.
噢，对，好的，我会的，再见
Oh, right. Right, okay, I will. Bye.
- 再见，孩子 - 再次感谢你所做的一切
- Goodbye, son. - Thanks again for everything!
- 等等，刘易斯，还有一件事 - 什么？
- Wait. Lewis, one more thing. - Yeah?
给将来的一点小提示 我永远是对的
Just a little tip for the future. I am always right.
即便是我错了，我还是对的
Even when I'm wrong, I'm right.
她是对的，如果我是你 我就会照她的话去做
She's right. I'd just go with it if I were you.
我的确如此
And I am.
那么你是绝对正确的
Then you're absolutely right.
好吧，我来了
All right, I'm coming.
又不是你将永远都见不到他们
Well, it's not like you're never gonna see them again.
他们毕竟都是你的家人
They are your family, after all.
等一等
Wait a minute.
你应该带我回到那科学展
You're supposed to take me back to the science fair.
我知道
I know.
那么我想你按错了号码
Well, I think you punched in the wrong numbers.
我们说好了 如果你修好了时光机器
We agreed that, if you fixed the time machine,
我会带你去见你的妈妈
I'd take you back to see your mom.
什么？
What?
说话算数
A deal's a deal.
我搞不懂 你为什么就这么让她走？
I don't get it. Why'd you just let her go?
因为我已经有了一个家庭
Because I already have a family.
我从来没想到我爸爸 会是我最好的朋友
I never thought my dad would be my best friend.
现在好了，别又让我来搭救你
Now, now, don't make me come and bail you out again.
我不会的
I won't.
记住，我有时光机器
Remember, I've got a time machine.
如果你又把事情弄糟了 我就会一直回来
If you mess up again, I'll just keep coming back
一直到你做对为止
till you get it right.
- 你记住那句座右铭了？ - 记住了
- You got that motto? - I got it.
别忘了
Don't forget it.
那是不可能的
I don't think that's possible.
你该走了
You better get going.
再见，威尔伯
See you later, Wilbur.
等一等！
Wait a minute!
顾博！顾博，醒一醒！
Goob! Goob, wake up!
什么？
What?
太棒了
That's it!
威勒斯坦先生 我知道出错的原因了
Mr Willerstein, I know what went wrong.
可以再给我一次机会吗？ 拜托
Can I have one more chance? Please!
来接我的人还没有到 所以快动手吧
My ride isn't here yet, so fire it up.
我需要一个志愿者
I need a volunteer.
现在告诉我一个输入日期
Now, just give me a date to input.
哦，让我想想
Well, now, let's see.
我的第一次科学展 我得到我的第一台显微镜的那天
There's my first science fair, the day I got my first microscope,
我畅游英吉利海峡的时光 我的第一枚雪橇金牌
the time I swam the English Channel, my first gold medal for the luge.
我知道了
I know.
妙极了
Perfect!
- 你这是太美了 - 他是个幸运的家伙
- You look gorgeous. - He's a lucky guy.
噢，它工作了
Oh! It works.
- 它工作了 - 它工作了
- It works! - It works.
你太漂亮了，露西尔
You look beautiful, Lucille.
布德？
Bud?
你们看到那没有？
- Would you look at that? - Whoa!
亲爱的！亲爱的 你来的刚好
Honey! Honey, you're just in time.
- 露西尔！ - 你成功了，刘易斯！你做到了！
- Lucille! - You did it, Lewis! You did it!
这发明太了不起了！
This invention is brilliant!
孩子，你是本次展览会 最有价值的参赛者！
Kid, you're this fair's MVP!
你的展示真是太精彩了
That was some show you put on.
你真是个特别的孩子
You're a real special kid,
但你看上去不像刘易斯 你更像…
but you don't look like a Lewis. You look more like a...
科尼利厄斯 我深有同感
Cornelius. I get that a lot.
哦，不！对不起，先生
Oh, no! Sorry, mister.
不要紧
No harm done.
弗兰克 我不是告诉过你不要乱跑的吗？
Frankie, what have I told you about running away?
-  弗兰克？ - 我的明星学生
- Frankie? - My star pupil.
我叫弗兰妮 我教青蛙音乐
My name's Franny, and I teach frogs music.
真的吗？
Really?
你知道青蛙比人类更具音乐才能吗？
You know that frogs have more musical ability than people?
但没有人相信我
But nobody believes me.
他们都认为我疯了
They all think I'm crazy.
你也认为我疯了吧
You think I'm crazy, too.
不，不，我觉得你是对的
No. No, I think you're right.
在这？那就是他
Over here? There he is.
孩子，我们想把你的故事 登在本地的报纸上
Kid, we'd like to get a story on you for the local paper.
等待着你的将是锦绣前程
You've got a bright future ahead of you.
让往事随风
Let it go
是啊
Yeah.
让衣袖卷到你的肩膀
Let it roll right off your shoulder
难道你还不知道
Don't you know
漫漫长夜已经过去
The hardest part is over
让它进来
Let it in
清者自清
Let your clarity define you
最后
In the end
我们只会记得那时的感觉
We will only just remember How it feels
让它悄然滑过
Let it slide
把烦恼抛之脑后
Let your troubles fall behind you
让它光芒四射
Let it shine
直到你感受到四周都是
Until you feel it all around you
我并不介意
And I don't mind
你是否会奔向我
If it's me you need to turn to
我们将共同渡过难关
We'll get by
到最后 心才是最重要的事情
It's the heart that really matters In the end
我们生命
Our lives are made
如此短促
In these small hours
充满希翼
These little wonders
充满磨难和命运转折
These twists and turns of fate
时光飞逝
Time falls away
虽说生命短促
But these small hours
我们依然幸存着
These small hours still remain
我不再唏嘘
All of my regret
往事如风
Will wash away somehow
但我依稀记得
But I cannot forget
我现在感觉真好
The way I feel right now
到此为止，我们不会往回看很远 我们保持奋勇前进，开辟新路和 尝试新的事物，因为我们充满好奇 好奇心指引我们不断开辟新途径
Around here...
保持奋勇前进　- 沃尔特・迪斯尼
Keep Moving Forward
TLF中文字幕站 http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net
TLF SUB http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net
我的未来不是梦
The future has arrived
The future's arrived
没有人会怀疑
Nobody can doubt
未来是我们所追求的梦
The future is what everything's about
你的未来会更好 我的未来会更好
It's better for you And it's better for me
未来会比所有人想象的还好
It's better than what everybody Thought it would be
我的未来不是梦
The future has arrived
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
未来不会死
The future's alive
永远活着
Alive as can be
只要睁开你的眼睛
Just open your eyes
就会看到
It's plain to see
只要不害怕
Just don't be afraid
保持奋勇前进
Just keep going on
一步一脚印 你就不会行差踏错
One step at a time And you can't go wrong
是时候去创造
It's time to create
去成长
Time to grow
如果你没有感觉错
If you feel right
世界，对，她在变
The world, yeah She's changing
难道这让你感觉不到生机？
Don't it make you feel alive?
我的未来不是梦
The future has arrived
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
未来不会死
The future's alive
我的未来悄然到来
The future is alive today
耶，耶
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
我的未来不是梦
The future's arrived
没有人能够怀疑
Nobody can doubt
未来是我们所追求的梦
The future is what everything's about
你的未来会更好 我的未来会更好
It's better for you It's better for me
未来会比所有人想象的还好
It's better than what everybody Thought it would be
是时候去创造
It's time to create
去成长
Time to grow
如果你没有感觉错
If you feel right
世界，对，她在变
The world, yeah She's changing
生命重新整理
And life's rearranging
难道这让你感觉不到生机？
Don't it make you feel alive?
我的未来不是梦
The future has arrived
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
未来不会死
The future's alive
我的未来悄然到来
The future is alive today
The future has arrived
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
我的未来不是梦
The future's alive
我的未来悄然到来
The future is alive today
我的未来不是梦
The future has arrived
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
未来不会死
The future's alive
未来今天还活着
The future is alive today
我的未来悄然到来
The future has arrived today
Waiting to cross the Rubicon
总在想我的立场
Wondering what side I'm on
还是年轻人时那些幻觉
What are these visions Of me as a young man
一只手臂挥舞着指点江山 另一只手臂挽着你的手
With one arm pointing And the other arm holding your hand?
需要一个计划 让你靠近
Needing a plan to keep you near
拉响笛声 为了你能听见
Blowing a horn so you can hear
如果这只是我的爱情和忠贞
If it was only my love and devotion
这世界会突然陷入
This world would suddenly be In a state of
波动
Commotion
情绪波动
Emotional commotion
我从来没有花前月下
I never get around Under the sun and the stars
也许因为我总是愤青
And I may be always frowning
但有天你会看到 在花前月下
But one day you will see Under the sun and the stars
你转过身来
You will turn around And I'll be
我正奔向你
In motion
情绪波动
Emotional commotion
情绪举动
Emotional motion